CLARANCE LIBERISTE NTWARI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | VUE.JS & TYPESCRIPT & NODE.JS



ABOUT

RWANDA KIGALI

☐ LIBERINTWARI@GMAIL.COM

CLARANCELIBERI

✓ CLARANCELIBERI
✓

IN/CLARANCE-LIBERISTE-NTWARI-27A484184

PROFICIENT LANGUAGES/FRAMEW ORK

PROFICIENT

TYPESCRIPT NODE.JS VUE.JS REACT.JS JAVA SPRING-BOOT GOLANG GIN

DATABASE

PROFICIENT

REDIS MONGODB MYSQL POSTGRESQL

OTHER LANGUAGES

WORKING

PYTHON GOLANG JAVA

DEVOPS

PROFICIENT

DOCKER ANSIBLE JENKINS GITLAB GCP AWS

METHODOLOGIES

SUMMARY

A software developer with over 4 years of experience developing modern web technologies solutions and has a passion for creativity, dedication, and ongoing personal growth. Has worked in small startups of 4 to large companies of 150 coworkers. Has led team of 10 in Agile methodologies and a track record of working remotely for 3 years, with a strong emphasis on team collaboration and efficient results

EXPERIENCE

PIVOT ACCESS, RWANDA (ONSITE)

FULL STACK ENGINEER, PROFESSIONAL INTERN

05/2023 - 10/2023

As part of my mandatory graduation internship from Rwanda Coding Academy, I played a pivotal role in the development of 'Tekana', a platform designed to manage the Rwanda National Police's daily operations, including traffic fines, driving license examinations, Moto Vehicle Inspection and license provisioning. Subsequently, as a seasoned Fullstack Engineer at Pivot Access here is what I did:

- Spearheaded the setup of micro frontends using React Next.js, enabling seamless collaboration across 7 independent modules without client disruptions.
- Led and mentored a team of 12 frontend developers, emphasizing code reviews and adherence to best coding practices to maintain high code quality.
- Architected and implemented a CI/CD pipeline using GitLab, pnpm, Docker and Kubernates, slashing the time required for linting, testing, and deploying multiple micro frontends.
- Championed creating and deploying the Tekana Components library, crafted with React, TypeScript, and TailwindCSS. Ensured its availability on npm and chromatic for widespread use by various frontend teams.
- Developed comprehensive CI/CD pipeline flow charts and frontend project documentation, simplifying the onboarding process for new team members.
- Advocated and provided guidance on the implementation of Atomic Design principles, fortifying consistency and scalability within the component library.
- Pioneered the adoption of monorepo using PNPM and TurboRepo within the team, streamlining code and tool standardization across different teams.

BRITISH PETROLEUM (BP), UK (REMOTE)

07/2022 - 03/2023

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

Delivered significant contributions to different teams, improved user experiences, managed monorepo architecture, implemented CI/CD pipelines, and helped keep track of action logs on the Superfleet platform.

- Created an audit log module that records all user actions for traceability, In audit log team.
- Created micro-frontends with Webpack module federation and Vue.js, which improved the developer experience by 70%.
- Created different components under the Atomic Design principle and Storybook while making the BP design system, reducing component dependency by 35%.
- Wrote Regression and Unit tests of the components in the BP design System.

HUNTERSOFBOOK, TURKEY (REMOTE)

04/2021 - 06/2022

SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER

Improved frontend development and user engagement at HuntersOfBook through storybook UI components and WYSIWYG editor.

- Created Component presentation with storybook, which improved Developer experience by 15%.
- Wrote unit test and integration test respecting TDD with Jest and testinglibrary
- Built end-to-end APIs using Nest.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, and Graphql.
- Developed a powerful WYSIWYG editor using Vue.js, an editor that made content writing smooth and faster with a 45% increase in efficiency for users.

PROFICIENT

AGILE SCRUM KANBAN ATOMIC DESIGN REM

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (PROFESSIONAL) KINYARWANDA (NATIVE) Wrote GitHub Action scripts for PRs, automating PR validations and automatic deployment, speeding up the normal manual process from 15mins to 55 secs.

MINISTRY OF ICT & RWANDA CODING ACADEMY, RWANDA(REMOTE)

SOFTWARE FULL STACK ENGINEER

Led a team and implemented features at Stunnity through analysis, design, mentorship, and efficient deployment using CI/CD pipeline.

- Led software analysis and design by making Software Requirement Specification (SRS), data dictionaries, DFD, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Integrated 4 backend microservices and Frontend on Gitlab pipeline and deployment.
- Led a team of 10, Reviewed code and taught the team how to use modern software methodologies.
- Implemented different features on live streaming calls and chat with Node.js and Vue.js
- Wrote component and e2e tests using the react-testing library and Cypress.

KURIOUS LTD, RWANDA(REMOTE)

07/2020 - 03/2021

08/2021 - 07/2022

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Developed tools for video and textual materials for students and a real-time messaging service for communication between students and teachers, improving the platform's front-end, making the platform more competitive with Coursera and Edx.

- Developed and led software analysis and design process, resulting in the successful creation of over 20 Software Requirement Specification (SRS) documents, data dictionaries, DFD diagrams, and user use cases.
- Setup Gitlab Enterprise server, Jenkins, Tomcat, PM2, Docker, and Kubernetes for Java, Node.js, and Vue.js app CI/CD.
- Implemented DevOps workflows on Digital Ocean, speeding CI/CD process by 30%.
- Developed Chat, Live Stream, and Students Forum modules, resulting in a 50% increase in user engagement and communication, utilizing technologies such as webRTC, socket.io, Vue.js, and Kurento.

VOLUNTEER

FUTURE SKILLS BOOTCAMP

12/2019 - 12/2019

WEB DEVELOPMENT MENTOR

Taught programming concepts to 350 children under 18 during a two week program.

- Covered five skills including HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and SQL.
- Guided and facilitated students in presenting final projects on demo day.
- Facilitated students in designing web pages within 7 days, helping to foster competitive programming and creative thinking skills.

EDUCATION

RWANDA CODING ACADEMY

02/2019 - 07/2022

ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE SOFTWARE PROGRAMMING & EMBEDDED SYSTEM